RYAN RUDMAN

Senior Front End Developer

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Rio de Janeiro Brazil

EMAIL

ryanrudman@yahoo.co.uk

NATIONALITY

South African / British

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

SASS

Javascript

React.js

Node.js

Git

Site Accessibility

Site Performance

Remote working

LANGUAGES

English

Portuguese

PROFILE

Senior Front End Developer with over a decade of commercial experience in working with big brand name clients in a leading global agency.

A capable coder, excellent problem solver, independant worker, quick learner and good team player with a proven track record of delivery and and remote work.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Front End Developer, Kin & Carta

remote

Mar 2014 — Present

- Working across multiple clients and projects ranging from content/data driven components to e-commerce sites to webGL based applications.
- Working closely with PM's and UX/designers, collaborating with cross-functional teams, following agile methodologies, and delivering projects within tight deadlines
- Implementing robust, responsive and performant UI's with cross-browser and cross-device compatability.
- Making use of both popular and customized CSS and JS libraries and frameworks to ensure optimal web performance and user experience.
- Lead FE developer across 4 projects taking ownership of FE, making tech stack and architectural decisions, assisting junior developers, ensuring code quality through regular reviews.

Notable clients include:

Toyota, Lexus, Asics, Trek. Unilever,

Forevermark, Expedia, M&G Investments,

Haglofs, Land Rover, NEFF

Front End Devloper, Essential Travel

London

Oct 2012 — Mar 2014

Worked on products catering for travel insurance comparison and booking services.

EDUCATION

CertHE in Web Design Technologies, Birkbeck, University of London London

Jan 2010 — Dec 2011